<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>In June on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-june/</link><description>Recent content in In June on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-june/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What tasks to focus on in June, by Huw Richards</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/images/2023-06-22-huw-s-garden-in-june.jpg" alt="Featured image of post What tasks to focus on in June, by Huw Richards" />&lt;p>In June, it’s warm and everything is growing fast, vegetables and weeds. Let’s look at what Huw is recommending to do this month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Huw Richards for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Huw Richards’ channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z18czx2fdzc">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tomatoes">Tomatoes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First, clean up the weeds at the bottom of the bottom of the plants&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, remove the &lt;em>suckers&lt;/em>, which are those stems coming out which will make your plant huge, but that will draw energy out of producing tomatoes. It’s especially true in cooler climates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cutting everything (suckers and leaves) below the first &lt;em>trust&lt;/em> or the first flowers will go a long way to keep the plant healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, clearing the base will increase airflow to prevent blite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, clear out the older leaves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See how Huw does it from &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/z18czx2fdzc?t=148">2:28 in the vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rain-and-watering">Rain and watering&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Gathering rain water, even in the UK for Huw, has become an issue. The vlog dates back to 2020! So imagine today…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With dry weather, keeping up with watering is hard…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, some vegetables will tend to bolt, meaning they will go to seed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With less water, you can also clean up the dead leaves to make sure diseases don’t spread and so that the garden looks tidy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="more-sowing">More sowing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can still see at this time of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-can-you-sow">What can you sow?&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>It will depend on your climate, your region. Even if you can find templates here and there, the real method is to use the guidelines of people around your area with experience and ask them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, because everyone has a unique garden, it’s through observation that you will know:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>based on the experience, year after year.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>based on the understanding of the weather.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>based on the nature of your soil.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="when-do-you-sow">When do you sow&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Prefer sowing when it’s cooler, especially during this month of summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="crops-progress-and-harvesting">Crops progress and harvesting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Again, through observation, you will need to check on your crops, checking for diseases, readiness for harvest and need of watering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, potatoes coming to flower are ready to harvest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huw usually waits a couple of weeks when he sees the flower buds of the plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Another tip" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Another tip&lt;/p>&lt;p>When you water lettuce, wait it from the top like shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water will then sink through the middle and it will give the full benefits to the lettuce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/images/watering-a-lettuce-from-the-top.jpg"
width="600"
height="295"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/images/watering-a-lettuce-from-the-top_hue6f9ccdeed69421aaae1cead71387588_149879_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/images/watering-a-lettuce-from-the-top_hue6f9ccdeed69421aaae1cead71387588_149879_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/what-tasks-to-focus-on-in-june-huw-richards/images/watering-a-lettuce-from-the-top_hue6f9ccdeed69421aaae1cead71387588_149879_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Watering a lettuce from the top"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="203"
data-flex-basis="488px"
>
&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="less-weeding">Less weeding&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Why?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The crops are growing and they leave little space to competing weeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>That isn’t the case for everything, of course. For example, bindweed can climb a crop and get its sunlight to continue to grow…&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="plan-for-the-next-planting">Plan for the next planting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Some crops will soon stop producing and it’s a good idea to the prepare the seedlings to plant whenever you will free garden space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s it for this vlog.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in June, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-06-05-a-man-weeding-alleys-between-garden-beds.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in June, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>We become quite busy in June with some harvesting, more sowing and weeding. Let’s look at how to optimize each task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d1OJTXRhy4k">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvesting-lettuce">Harvesting lettuce&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The harvest of lettuce is simple, yet, you can perform it in such a way that will help enrich the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like Moreno, I cut my lettuce at the ground level. This lets the root to rot in the soil, providing food for the soil’s web.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The important part to remember, though: cut low enough to prevent a new sprouting of the lettuce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno cuts all the lettuces he needs at once before performing a first basic cleaning of the bottom of each lettuce from the damaged and wilted leaves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, in market gardening, keep track of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>what you harvested,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>where you harvested the crops from&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the date,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the quantity&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Use a garden journal" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Use a garden journal&lt;/p>&lt;p>Moreno shares some details about the journals that he keeps up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It allows you to record all the important information from the farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in addition to the information above, it’s a good idea to record:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the number of days to maturity of crops depending on the period of the year&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the time to perform certain tasks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The goal is to gather the information will help make the market gardening more profitable.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Coming back to the lettuce, it’s important to lower the temperature of the salad to keep fresh longer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno performs the task of using a cold-water bath, plunging the lettuce’s heads upside down in water for a couple of seconds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, it helps clean up the dirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the process &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/d1OJTXRhy4k?t=150">at 2:30 in the vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaving the lettuces to drip out for a while is important after the washing&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="eggplant-and-pepper-support-system">Eggplant and pepper support system&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Why do you need support for eggplants and peppers? In the fruits are big, the plant may not stay up because of the heavy load.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno uses wood stakes that he sets every 5 plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Strings attached to wood stakes"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, every 25 cm, as the plant grows, he sets 2 strings, in each side of the plant that will hold it over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="2 strings hold the plant up and tall"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="weeding">Weeding&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Who wants to weed? Not me.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>Just yesterday, I spent 1h15 weeding. What Moreno shares here isn’t applicable to all situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this year, I spent the time covering with a big amount of cardboard and woodchips the alleys of my garden and it has made a big difference so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is still weeds coming out. But the roots are shallow and the weeds are really easy to pull up, especially the bindweed and couch grass.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Moreno uses two methods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a tick layer of compost, of about 10 cm, for the cultivated areas,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a tick layer of woodchip, of about 5 cm, for the pathways.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This method doesn’t remove all weeds nor does it prevent weeds to grow. But it reduces a lot of the amount of them, resulting in a much lower time consumption weeding out the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For market gardening, the no-dig approach really brings its benefits to keep a clean and weed-free garden. It’s important when you need to spend time sowing, planting and harvesting rather than weeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno weeds his garden 4 times a year, usually when he replaces a harvested crop with the next crop to sow or plant.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="The key to weed-free garden" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">The key to weed-free garden&lt;/p>&lt;p>Never let weeds get established.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a weed goes to seed, remove it and keep a good eye on that area to remove the new weeds from that area.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Another trick Moreno shares: for the edges, cover them with landscape fabric and a good 5 cm of woodchips.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>On my property, we have a lot of historical weeds:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>couch grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bindweeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>brambles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Those are the most difficult weeds to get rid of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like I said above, I’m trying to weed them out using the no-dig approach as well using cardboard (&lt;a href="../../../tag/charles-dowding">from Charles Dowding’s tips&lt;/a>) and woodchips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will take a few years to reach a point where the weeds are manageable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far this year, the bindweed is what I see the most. The funny thing is that it runs its roots below the cardboard until it can get out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s therefore very easy to pull them out, and a long string of root with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll keep on adding more cardboard and woodchips on top, which will build up a good soil structure and will kill the weeds.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You liked this article? Consider subscribing to help me write more :)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>