<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self-Sufficiency on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/self-sufficiency/</link><description>Recent content in Self-Sufficiency on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/self-sufficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to STOP Buying Compost (Tips For Compost Self-Sufficiency), by Huw Richards</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-11-21-how-to-stop-buying-compost-tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to STOP Buying Compost (Tips For Compost Self-Sufficiency), by Huw Richards" />&lt;p>Making your own compost is key to self-sufficiency and Huw will provide us with a few tips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Huw Richards for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Huw Richards’s channel. You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xbwVlBzAGZU">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="starting-disclaimer">Starting disclaimer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No everybody has access to the same resources and the same amount of each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, we have different numbers of spaces to make and store the compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this vlog, Huw showcases *his method to become self-sufficient in compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="definition-of-self-sufficiency">Definition of self-sufficiency&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It can be different for all of us. To Huw, the goal is to create all the mulching compost he needs for the garden and for transplanting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, at the time of the shooting, he still purchases seed compost (e.g., potting compost) because he hasn’t perfected his own yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Self-sufficiency is a journey that takes time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="types-of-compost">Types of compost&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We find the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>standard compost, the one you apply in a layer of 2 to 3 cm each year on your beds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inoculated compost&lt;/li>
&lt;li>nutrishous compost&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and the fourth one can be in &lt;em>The Living Soil Handbook&lt;/em> from Jesse Frost.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It’s available &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3EMDfKB">in France&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3VeWYIq">in the UK&lt;/a> and the&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3ENTBmn"> US&lt;/a>. It provides clear and detailed tips to build up life in your soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jesse describes the four types of composts in depth.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-much-compost">How much compost&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Huw’s favorite bed size is a 3 m by 1.2 m with a depth of 20 cm (rough estimate from the vlog).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/huw-beds.jpg"
width="600"
height="301"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/huw-beds_hu9811ed1edf1c9787eeee0d3b569fff79_207556_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/huw-beds_hu9811ed1edf1c9787eeee0d3b569fff79_207556_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/huw-beds_hu9811ed1edf1c9787eeee0d3b569fff79_207556_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Garden beds"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="199"
data-flex-basis="478px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a mulch layer of 2 cm, it will require 100 liters of compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Count the number of beds you have and time that by 100 liters. It will give the compost amount you need for your garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, take a 20% extra so you’re sure not to run out.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>Of course, not everyone can build a garden with the same rectangular frame.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, my garden has a weird shape, so the beds are rarely rectangular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So make your beds with creativity, using the space efficiently,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, using the material you have available for free can decrease your bill.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="making-compost">Making compost&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Remember: compost is decomposed material, it means that the original materials have been broken down and you will get about one third in the volume of what you put in on the heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, this ratio is dependent on what you put on the heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you look at the compost you need to make, you might feel overwhelmed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Huw suggests to spread the load.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="making-compost-in-the-alleys">Making compost in the alleys&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Huw spreads all kinds of material in the alleys between the beds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It equals to about 10 cm to 15 cm layer. When it&amp;rsquo;s ready, he sifts it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That way he can get about 200 liters of compost, enough for the two beds.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="chicken-compost">Chicken compost&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Checkout &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/edibleacres">EdibleAcres&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/GeoffLawtonOnline">Geoff Lawton&lt;/a> channels that talk about this topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The advantage of chicken compost is that the chicken will eat the seeds they find in the bedding.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="worm-compost">Worm compost&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This compost is usually very nutritious. It’s used more as a supplement rather than a sole use for your garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hot-beds">Hot beds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It’s more a gardening technique than a compost making technique.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, it’s about using the warmth of compost in the making to grow vegetables you wouldn’t grow in certain times of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And at the end, you have harvested the crops that grew in those hot beds and you will find yourself with a huge amount of great quality compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sourcing-materials">Sourcing materials&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="grass-clippings">Grass clippings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/grass-clippings.jpg"
width="600"
height="300"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/grass-clippings_hu567cc516c1f98de01051671d7de45c38_157120_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/grass-clippings_hu567cc516c1f98de01051671d7de45c38_157120_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/grass-clippings_hu567cc516c1f98de01051671d7de45c38_157120_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bag of freshly cut grass clippings"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="200"
data-flex-basis="480px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huw thinks it could work well on the previously mentioned deep mulch chicken compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Always be on the lookup" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Always be on the lookup&lt;/p>&lt;p>When you make your compost, you will need to be mindful to the material you can gather to make your compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People throw a lot of things that can go on the compost heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m preparing to look around my area to see who would be giving away their grass clippings, saving them time as they don’t have to go the local public waste factory.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="woodchips">Woodchips&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Woodchips come not only from the freshly cut branches, but also the sawmill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first type, called fragmented rameal wood, comes from the small branches. Their width shouldn&amp;rsquo;t exceed 7 cm in diameter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those branches contain more nutrients than bigger pieces and, with two to three years, you can use it as compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saw-dust">Saw dust&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Saw dust creates a fine texture because of its natural form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So using compost with a good portion of saw dust might just be the good recipe for potting compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you may wonder if it isn’t too high in carbon and that it might suck the nitrogen out of the ground. Well, it’s always a matter of balance. You won’t apply saw dust as is the beds. You will mix it with some green material and let it degrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>Having used saw dust the past year to make my compost from grass clipping mixed the saw dust and kitchen waste, I have to say that the result in terms of texture and look seems promising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will use it next year and I’ll report my findings.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="A word of caution" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">A word of caution&lt;/p>&lt;p>Make sure the wood saw dust you collect is free from preservatives before you plan to put it on a compost heap.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="dead-leaves">Dead leaves&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Same as saw dust, dead leaves are available and cheap, and mixed well with green materials, you can create a great compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I use leaves as my winter duvet for the garden in a 10 cm to 20 cm layer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I don’t have the best orientation in the winter with about four and a half hours of sun (weather permitting), I don’t plant anything during the winter months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year was my first year applying this covering and by the end of this year harvest, I can tell you, the leaves have all disappeared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it has helped to create a smoother soil, from which I can more easily pull out the weeds.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="coffee-grounds">Coffee grounds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/coffee-ground.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/coffee-ground_hufcd4a8035f6106ecce8777a6baf45d97_123717_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/coffee-ground_hufcd4a8035f6106ecce8777a6baf45d97_123717_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/coffee-ground_hufcd4a8035f6106ecce8777a6baf45d97_123717_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Coffee in the hand of someone"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s high in nitrogen, so you can assimilate it to a green material.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-materials">Other materials&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Obviously, your kitchen waste participate to filling the heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I put in 5 liters of kitchen waste daily, mainly vegetables waste.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The local highly available weeds can become a great source of material. Huw has a lot of bracken (&lt;em>Pteridium&lt;/em>) around his garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/braken-leaves.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/braken-leaves_hu7d4aead576404ac756a08c48fdb220c4_194983_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/braken-leaves_hu7d4aead576404ac756a08c48fdb220c4_194983_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/tips-for-compost-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/images/braken-leaves_hu7d4aead576404ac756a08c48fdb220c4_194983_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A lot of bracken leaves"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardboard suits a lot of applications in the garden: from covering in the No Dig method to brown material additions to the heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Glues on cardboard" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Glues on cardboard&lt;/p>&lt;p>Huw tells glues are almost always strach-based, meaning they come from a plant-based source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, verify your sources.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Huw lives near the coast so he harvests seaweed from the coastline after a storm or a high tide.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="How to remove the salt" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">How to remove the salt&lt;/p>&lt;p>Lay it on the ground a little while then let it dry and it will be ready to use.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Finally, using cover crops produces a lot of materials to bulk up the compost heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check out the channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/davidthegood">David the Good&lt;/a> as he explains it in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@davidthegood/search?query=cover%20crop">these vlogs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="set-goals-that-you-can-attain">Set goals that you can attain&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first challenge is to gather the materials. Finding a place to pile it up won’t be a challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So for your first year, brainstorm:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>where you can get the materials,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>then build your heap using wood pallets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>finally, start filling the first heap&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Within a year, you will have your very own homemade compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>My goal for the 2022–2023 year is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Finding more sources of grass clippings closer to home, even if I can get a trailer-full of it from the mowing my company loan (I know nobody spray anything on it).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Asking my local organic store for coffee grounds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting more saw dust from the local sawmill that is only 5 min from my house.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Growing more comfrey because it gives out huge leaves!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>The Simple Way to Becoming Self-Sufficient in Food, by Huw Richards</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-10-02-a-vegetable-garden.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Simple Way to Becoming Self-Sufficient in Food, by Huw Richards" />&lt;p>Growing your own food is a great skill to learn. You can start on a small area to become familiar with the basics. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the first steps to become more self-sufficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Thanks to Huw Richards for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Huw Richards&amp;rsquo;s channel. You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HmQqsTM8co">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="food-self-sufficiency-a-definition">Food self-sufficiency: a definition&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is the goal to grow your own food you need to eat every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is becoming independent and not needing anything from shops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It requires a lot of careful planning and can become overwhelming if you set yourself goals that are too high.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, you will have to make some sacrifices, not only regarding the food you can actually be self-sufficient with, but also the time you have to grow your own food and what you can grow in your garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is about asking oneself the question: what is the ultimate goal of food self-sufficiency?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-start">How to start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Set small targets to start that are easy to reach and move on to more ambitious ones, without ever going too fast too soon. Otherwise you will crush the goal of self-sufficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember: self-sufficiency doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen overnight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, self-sufficiency doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you have to grow food 365 days a year. Instead, try to perform work to reach part-time self-sufficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing some food for a specific period that you know will be more doable in &lt;em>your situation&lt;/em> might just be enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>you can grow salads from April to November and be self-sufficient in salad that period&lt;/li>
&lt;li>you can grow onions and be self-sufficient through autumn and winter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="what-group-crops-to-start-with">What group crops to start with&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>They are easy to grow and versatile in the kitchen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="salads">Salads&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>cut and come again&lt;/em> salads are the best (take what you need in leaves while leaving the plant produce).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/salads-with-alliums.jpg"
width="600"
height="304"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/salads-with-alliums_huab174cb4ec0170f88f691fd5c16332a6_130496_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/salads-with-alliums_huab174cb4ec0170f88f691fd5c16332a6_130496_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/salads-with-alliums_huab174cb4ec0170f88f691fd5c16332a6_130496_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Salads with Alliums crops to help with the slugs"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="197"
data-flex-basis="473px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a couple, you can easily be self-sufficient in salads with a 4 x 4 feet raised bed (equivalent to 1.3 m x 1.3 m, so less than 2 m²) during the growing season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To go further to reach self-sufficiency throughout the year, you can use:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>some clothes and fleeces to extend the season
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/fleece-tunnel.jpg"
width="600"
height="301"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/fleece-tunnel_hu03cdf024d013bd45aabfed0da8105e83_169786_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/fleece-tunnel_hu03cdf024d013bd45aabfed0da8105e83_169786_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/fleece-tunnel_hu03cdf024d013bd45aabfed0da8105e83_169786_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A fleece tunnel"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="199"
data-flex-basis="478px"
>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a small greenhouse&lt;/li>
&lt;li>or a polytunnel&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="potatoes">Potatoes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough garden space, grow them in 25 to 30 liter containers and start harvesting them from mid-June.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are easy to store through winter. It is done in a dark and cool place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="onions">Onions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is really easy to grow and to store them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The production could give enough to last from late summer to winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="kale">Kale&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can start kale in mid-March to April and expect to harvest leaves from mid to late June all the way through winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And even in the next year, in March, April and May, you will get a lot of flowers shoots that will give you more food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a lot of varieties to choose from, so if you are not keen with the curly kale, you can try others, like the red Russian kale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/red-russian-kale.jpg"
width="600"
height="298"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/red-russian-kale_hu66fde1d208005e95f116db9e5f93fdbb_137642_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/red-russian-kale_hu66fde1d208005e95f116db9e5f93fdbb_137642_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/the-simple-way-to-food-self-sufficiency-huw-richards/red-russian-kale_hu66fde1d208005e95f116db9e5f93fdbb_137642_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A patch of a red Russian kale"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="201"
data-flex-basis="483px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="annual-herbs">Annual herbs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Even if perennial herbs (meaning living for several years) would be easy to pick, we will gain more satisfaction from fresh herbs during the growing season, like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>coriander.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-much-do-i-need-to-grow-something">How much do I need to grow something&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Everyone is different so you are the one who can know how much you and your household eat throughout the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, look at the core staples you eat in your case throughout the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, estimate:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>how much you need of a staple per week
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>for example 2 bulbs of garlic per week&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>how long you need that staple: 1 month, 6 months, all year
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>for example 4 months&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So in the example, that gives us 2 bulbs x 4 months (12 weeks) = 24 plants of garlic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be aware that you will need to think about storage for some food if you want to have it available for longer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to take into account the potential failures, so add 20 to 25% to the estimate, so in the example, we will need an extra 6 plants of garlic.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal tip" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal tip&lt;/p>&lt;p>I have started in August 2022 to track the quantity of the food purchases we make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is easy today to scan a grocery ticket and convert it using an image to text online tool like &lt;a href="https://www.onlineocr.net/">Online OCR&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While it is not perfect depending on your receipt quality, it helps a lot to build a journal of your purchases week by week and only take a couple of minutes for each ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a while, you will be able to build a predefined list of produces you buy regularly and you might not need to scan and convert anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can track your purchases using &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1hScfACex3yjX-Nu5FUy4wTN7csYKyGf75TEJKwAem9A/edit?usp=sharing">this free Google sheet template&lt;/a> over a month or a year (you will need to be patient for a year long tracking).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please feel free to use it as a template. At the end, it will be very quick to identity how much you need from a given crop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will need to adjust the values in the &amp;ldquo;Constants&amp;rdquo; tab as you go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a while, it will be easy to input your purchase if you buy by the season and if you are regular. &lt;a href="https://iamjeremie.me/page/contact-me/">Contact me if you have questions&lt;/a> on how to use the sheet or if you want me to demo it in a video.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Test different varieties: some may not work while others can be very successful. Don&amp;rsquo;t beat yourself up if the first try doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also embrace seasonality: don&amp;rsquo;t try to push against the natural cycle. Tomatoes are a summer crop, while cabbage and squashes are more a winter one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What benefits do you get from eating out of season?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>you will have more fresh produce to eat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>you will have to be more creative on how to use the crops you get. See &lt;a href="https://farmerandchef.co.uk/blog">Huw and Sam&amp;rsquo;s blog for recipes&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Look at what is special about every single season and you will become of more self-sufficient.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>