<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intercropping on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/intercropping/</link><description>Recent content in Intercropping on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/intercropping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Harvesting Garlic and Succession Planting, by Huw Richards</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/harvesting-garlic-and-succession-planting-huw-richards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/harvesting-garlic-and-succession-planting-huw-richards/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-10-04-harvesting-garlic-and-succession-planting-salads-huw-richards-hero.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Harvesting Garlic and Succession Planting, by Huw Richards" />&lt;p>Succession planting the act to sow and plant another crops following the harvesting of a previous one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Huw Richards for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Huw Richards&amp;rsquo;s channel. You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S8ivP0opZTE">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tip-for-sprouted-garlic-who-comes-up-early-in-spring">Tip for sprouted garlic who comes up early in spring&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Covering the ground with compost will help nourish the garlic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-follow-garlic">What can follow garlic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Huw sowed mustards, rocket salads and radishes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="share-excess-yields-with-neighbors-and-friends">Share excess yields with neighbors and friends&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you grow your own food and you have excess, it is a great idea to share it, make exchanges or even donate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is really a value that needs to expand.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-about-intercropping">What about intercropping&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I find that some crops, like lettuce and strawberries, struggle with pests, named slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have tried in the past growing shallot around strawberries and I think it worked to keep the slugs away, far better than ash, beer traps or egg shells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kathleen Henderson, &lt;a href="https://rootsandboots.com">from Roots and Boots&lt;/a>, shared in &lt;a href="https://rootsandboots.com/intercropping-lettuce-with-garlic/">an article on the topic&lt;/a> listing the advantages of intercropping lettuce and garlic in three points:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>increased yield: grow more in less space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>weed control: vegetable like lettuce help to block out weeds around slower growing plants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pest management: intercropping increases biodiversity in the garden, which can help to confuse harmful insects&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My favorite benefit is clear the third one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is your experience on the topic?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>