<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Dutch Farmer on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/the-dutch-farmer/</link><description>Recent content in The Dutch Farmer on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/the-dutch-farmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Market Gardening in July, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-07-03-bumblebees-on-echinacea-flowers.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in July, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>What can you do in July? Moreno walks us through his garden to show us the different gardening tasks to perform this month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SaujrNQ2iOw">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvest-of-garlic">Harvest of garlic&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/harvested-garlic-from-in-between-strawberries.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/harvested-garlic-from-in-between-strawberries_hued5e432bcfa0f493c23db8fda852b699_239207_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/harvested-garlic-from-in-between-strawberries_hued5e432bcfa0f493c23db8fda852b699_239207_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/harvested-garlic-from-in-between-strawberries_hued5e432bcfa0f493c23db8fda852b699_239207_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Harvested garlic from in between strawberries"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It usually happens early on the month of July.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>This year 2023 was my first year to grow garlic and with over 100 cloves planted, we are happy with the green garlic we enjoy in May and June and the dry garlic we’ll enjoy the rest of the summer.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Moreno is quite happy with the multi-crop beds. Remember, he talked about it in &lt;a href="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/">his March episode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He shares an interesting fact about soft neck garlic: it can store up to 12 months! The hard neck garlic usually doesn’t store longer than 6 months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you harvested the garlic, you will need to cure them, e.g., clean them for storage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is important to remember that to dry them, you shouldn’t set them in direct sunlight, yet they need to be hanging in a ventilated, warm and dry place. It will take 4 to 6 weeks to dry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fruit-trees">Fruit trees&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/ridiculously-loaded-pear-tree.jpg"
width="600"
height="314"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/ridiculously-loaded-pear-tree_hu5cfa7bafa26cf83823da7c1cf9c1abd0_229514_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/ridiculously-loaded-pear-tree_hu5cfa7bafa26cf83823da7c1cf9c1abd0_229514_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/ridiculously-loaded-pear-tree_hu5cfa7bafa26cf83823da7c1cf9c1abd0_229514_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ridiculously loaded pear tree"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="191"
data-flex-basis="458px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees provide many benefits:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>extra food&lt;/li>
&lt;li>shade for the crops under them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>help preventing bolting on the spring crops&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It can become more difficult, however, to have fruit trees above market gardening crops, adding more labor to harvest them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So plant your vegetable beds well to make it easier.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tomatoes">Tomatoes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/tomatoes-under-a-polytunnel.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/tomatoes-under-a-polytunnel_hu464ce9735ab1d6185afd743263ee1202_228966_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/tomatoes-under-a-polytunnel_hu464ce9735ab1d6185afd743263ee1202_228966_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-07/market-gardening-in-july-the-dutch-farmer/images/tomatoes-under-a-polytunnel_hu464ce9735ab1d6185afd743263ee1202_228966_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Tomatoes under a polytunnel"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see above that Moreno uses as much as possible the available space, planting lettuces or flowers at the bottom of tomatoes or cucumbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In market gardening, tomatoes have a highly profitable value, even though the work you need to perform more important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you harvest them, it is important to harvest them not fully ripe; otherwise it will shorten the time you have to sell them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though you harvest them not fully ripe, they continue to ripen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All this applies to large tomatoes. In fact, the cherry and cocktail types are better harvested fully ripe because they sell more easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>July is the month when harvesting is the focus and it is when you will make most of the year’s revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, soon, it will be time to prepare for the fall and winter crops.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in June, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-06-05-a-man-weeding-alleys-between-garden-beds.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in June, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>We become quite busy in June with some harvesting, more sowing and weeding. Let’s look at how to optimize each task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d1OJTXRhy4k">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvesting-lettuce">Harvesting lettuce&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The harvest of lettuce is simple, yet, you can perform it in such a way that will help enrich the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like Moreno, I cut my lettuce at the ground level. This lets the root to rot in the soil, providing food for the soil’s web.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The important part to remember, though: cut low enough to prevent a new sprouting of the lettuce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno cuts all the lettuces he needs at once before performing a first basic cleaning of the bottom of each lettuce from the damaged and wilted leaves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As usual, in market gardening, keep track of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>what you harvested,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>where you harvested the crops from&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the date,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the quantity&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Use a garden journal" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Use a garden journal&lt;/p>&lt;p>Moreno shares some details about the journals that he keeps up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It allows you to record all the important information from the farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in addition to the information above, it’s a good idea to record:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the number of days to maturity of crops depending on the period of the year&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the time to perform certain tasks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The goal is to gather the information will help make the market gardening more profitable.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Coming back to the lettuce, it’s important to lower the temperature of the salad to keep fresh longer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno performs the task of using a cold-water bath, plunging the lettuce’s heads upside down in water for a couple of seconds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, it helps clean up the dirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the process &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/d1OJTXRhy4k?t=150">at 2:30 in the vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaving the lettuces to drip out for a while is important after the washing&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="eggplant-and-pepper-support-system">Eggplant and pepper support system&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Why do you need support for eggplants and peppers? In the fruits are big, the plant may not stay up because of the heavy load.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno uses wood stakes that he sets every 5 plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/strings-attached-to-wood-stakes_huda0aa47b3a74cb33f6a994adbc1861a7_160442_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Strings attached to wood stakes"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, every 25 cm, as the plant grows, he sets 2 strings, in each side of the plant that will hold it over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-06/market-gardening-in-june-the-dutch-farmer/images/2-strings-hold-the-plant-up-and-tall_huc19fa306a4a3fc18d2f8a9ef3c049a35_174617_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="2 strings hold the plant up and tall"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="weeding">Weeding&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Who wants to weed? Not me.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>Just yesterday, I spent 1h15 weeding. What Moreno shares here isn’t applicable to all situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this year, I spent the time covering with a big amount of cardboard and woodchips the alleys of my garden and it has made a big difference so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is still weeds coming out. But the roots are shallow and the weeds are really easy to pull up, especially the bindweed and couch grass.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Moreno uses two methods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a tick layer of compost, of about 10 cm, for the cultivated areas,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a tick layer of woodchip, of about 5 cm, for the pathways.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This method doesn’t remove all weeds nor does it prevent weeds to grow. But it reduces a lot of the amount of them, resulting in a much lower time consumption weeding out the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For market gardening, the no-dig approach really brings its benefits to keep a clean and weed-free garden. It’s important when you need to spend time sowing, planting and harvesting rather than weeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno weeds his garden 4 times a year, usually when he replaces a harvested crop with the next crop to sow or plant.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="The key to weed-free garden" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">The key to weed-free garden&lt;/p>&lt;p>Never let weeds get established.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a weed goes to seed, remove it and keep a good eye on that area to remove the new weeds from that area.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Another trick Moreno shares: for the edges, cover them with landscape fabric and a good 5 cm of woodchips.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>On my property, we have a lot of historical weeds:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>couch grass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bindweeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>brambles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Those are the most difficult weeds to get rid of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like I said above, I’m trying to weed them out using the no-dig approach as well using cardboard (&lt;a href="../../../tag/charles-dowding">from Charles Dowding’s tips&lt;/a>) and woodchips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will take a few years to reach a point where the weeds are manageable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far this year, the bindweed is what I see the most. The funny thing is that it runs its roots below the cardboard until it can get out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s therefore very easy to pull them out, and a long string of root with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll keep on adding more cardboard and woodchips on top, which will build up a good soil structure and will kill the weeds.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You liked this article? Consider subscribing to help me write more :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in May, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-05-01-gooseberry-bush-with-fruits.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in May, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>In May, it’s getting serious, with a lot of crops to plant and to start harvesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y-pugIGF5TU">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="growing-food-is-an-invaluable-skill">Growing food is an invaluable skill&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I can’t agree more with the statement that Moreno made about growing food yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It not only yields food for your family, but also, it teaches a better understanding of the environment around.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stewardship&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the conducting, supervising, or managing of something. Especially : the careful and responsible management of something entrusted to one’s care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/stewardship">Webster dictionary&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We’re stewards of this planet, meaning we should manage to the best of abilities so that it’s sustained. We therefore shouldn’t exploit it like we can see the powerful corporations act.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we’re nearing summer, cherries will be ripened by the end of the month or early next month, as usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I have seen news articles talking about the farmers in Ardèche, France, not knowing how to fight off the pest (the &lt;a href="https://www.agropomme.ca/Documentation_publique/DSUZUKII/2BiologieDsuzukii.pdf">drosophilia suzikki&lt;/a>](&lt;a href="https://www.agropomme.ca/Documentation_publique/DSUZUKII/2BiologieDsuzukii.pdf">https://www.agropomme.ca/Documentation_publique/DSUZUKII/2BiologieDsuzukii.pdf&lt;/a>)) that destroys the ripe cherries, when left untreated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, just for the sake of &lt;em>producing profit&lt;/em> (which the poor growers aren’t receiving much of it), they will spray chemicals that are known to be dangerous for our health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won’t make a case here about it in this article. It’ll let you do &lt;strong>your research&lt;/strong> and make &lt;strong>your own conclusions&lt;/strong> from those starting articles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://agriculture.gouv.fr/la-france-suspend-les-importations-de-cerises-traitees-au-phosmet">France suspends imports of cherries treated with phosmet&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.pleinchamp.com/actualite/mouche-asiatique-sur-cerise-on-ne-va-peut-etre-pas-miser-sur-la-tramontane">Asian fly on cherry: “We may not bet on the Tramontana”&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.lafranceagricole.fr/cultures/article/836985/les-producteurs-de-cerises-en-colere">Angry cherry growers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Yes, the alternatives, like nets, which cost a lot more, or traps, which don’t always fall on the effectiveness side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But do they realize that they are slaves of the system which:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>impose on the growers to buy the chemicals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and sell the produce for almost nothing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and finally sell drugs to the general population from big pharma to heal the diseases that the chemicals create…&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>What a vicious cycle!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, why not learn to grow your own food? Yes, a cherry tree will take time to grow and yield a good harvest, at least, you can choose to eat healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isn’t that better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, growing your own food requires:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>some land, but you’d be a surprise
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D1q8PlgPOIs">how much a little piece of land can produce&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and what techniques exist to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y9ysNE5bLdk">optimize the small areas&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some resources (compost mainly, that can be found in your local quarry, which I discovered only a couple of months ago) and tools (your hands ;))&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some &lt;em>ressourfulness&lt;/em> by starting to &lt;a href="../../../tag/gardening">read my articles on gardening&lt;/a> or watching the YouTube channels I document in those articles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some seeds from organic sources.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is key that they produce crops that yield you new fertile seeds for free.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;strong>will to start&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="where-to-start">Where to start&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Plant perennial herbs and flowers and bush berries that can yield quickly and in surprising quantities of healthy food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>comfrey,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>rosemary,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>thyme,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>vervain,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>goji berry,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>black berry,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gooseberry,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>raspberry&lt;/li>
&lt;li>black currant,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>red currant,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="high-tunnel-and-aphid-attack">High tunnel and aphid attack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/images/aphids-suck-juice-out-of-the-leaves-of-plant-to-look-like-the-above.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hubf3eed6216a604e1afbf6c66b59462d0_162049_563590ec141abb23c0d88b256d5d8887.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hubf3eed6216a604e1afbf6c66b59462d0_162049_21985928fad68a925dd35882f3155356.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-05/market-gardening-in-may-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hubf3eed6216a604e1afbf6c66b59462d0_162049_3fdea31867f3ca6b4305be47cac3319a.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Aphids suck juice out of the leaves of plant to look like the above"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aphid’s infection causes the leaves of the plant to curl and kill the plant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To fix that, you have 2 options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>simply make a black soap solution and spray it onto the leaves to wash off the aphids,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>introduce the ladybug and its larvae, which you can:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>collect around you leave and move at the dinner table&lt;/li>
&lt;li>buy them online, if you don’t have any into the wild&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="plant-trees-and-fruit-trees-when-starting-a-farm">Plant trees and fruit trees when starting a farm&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The long-term view of a farming enterprise doesn’t take into account the only mart gardening, which can yield crops straight away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Planting perennials, fruit bushes and fruit trees will provide you food with little effort, when it’s designed to work seamlessly with nature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees provide shade. Bushes provide shelter for insects and wildlife.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To become more resilient, we need to increase the diversity and systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~ Moreno, the Dutch Farmer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Small farms are extremely important for the well-being of communities today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start your garden today!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more articles like this one, consider subscribing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in April, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-04-03-a-tool-to-make-holes-in-the-soil-to-transplant.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in April, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>April is a month when you will transplant a lot and there are steps that you can follow to make it successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JgWrFENqy0">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-transplant-efficiently">How to transplant efficiently&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="prepare-no-dig-beds">Prepare No Dig beds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The No Dig approach is a way to make market gardening successful because it works similarly to how nature works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is about:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>not digging or tilling the soil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>keeping the soil covered at all times with organic matter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Why is it an efficient approach?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It feeds the soil web&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It keeps the weeds away&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It makes it very easy to transplant.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-spreads-compost.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-spreads-compost_huc3f34468b4959a1d4745665ed318c64b_224731_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-spreads-compost_huc3f34468b4959a1d4745665ed318c64b_224731_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-spreads-compost_huc3f34468b4959a1d4745665ed318c64b_224731_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A man spreading compost"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tools-to-use">Tools to use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can find a variety of tools to mark the beds:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a wide rake with rigid plastic tubes spaced to your needs
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-uses-a-rake-with-3-rigid-plastic-tube-to-mark-the-bed-before-transplanting-plants.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hua130eb869416d8aff9615b771e3151a4_213943_0f5f08b3c29fdbb4e5f88dad523c9a3d.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hua130eb869416d8aff9615b771e3151a4_213943_8ed4b15c29ea57cfc1656ca1d6e61430.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hua130eb869416d8aff9615b771e3151a4_213943_ccb53a5fa3e96305e43f90be7f5e751c.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A man using a rake with 3 rigid plastic tube to mark the bed before transplanting plants"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/preparing-the-rake-with-the-rigid-plastic-tubes.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/preparing-the-rake-with-the-rigid-plastic-tubes_huc8d08e67bd36f0880b9c7d32a951d8f9_203388_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/preparing-the-rake-with-the-rigid-plastic-tubes_huc8d08e67bd36f0880b9c7d32a951d8f9_203388_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/preparing-the-rake-with-the-rigid-plastic-tubes_huc8d08e67bd36f0880b9c7d32a951d8f9_203388_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Preparing the rake with the rigid plastic tubes"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a bed roller with pikes to make holes in the soil
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2023-04-03-a-tool-to-make-holes-in-the-soil-to-transplant.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="A tool that helps making holes in the soil to transplant the seedlings"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a grider
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-using-a-grider-tool-to-mark-the-bed-before-transplanting-plants.jpg"
width="600"
height="307"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu2b6a18447e1cbc82130feef62b3e21b2_235383_c4f5f713918990a756b2d1a48ef3ba5e.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu2b6a18447e1cbc82130feef62b3e21b2_235383_11f5e3448d8136fd6734c3ad31eaf306.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu2b6a18447e1cbc82130feef62b3e21b2_235383_cd9c9692b41ef31057397edc4f007856.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A man using a grider tool to mark the bed before transplanting plants"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="195"
data-flex-basis="469px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The rake is the cheaper and the grider is the most efficient tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="transplanting-from-500httpsyoutube1jgwrfenqy0t300">Transplanting (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1JgWrFENqy0?t=300">from 5:00&lt;/a>)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once the beds are ready, you will need to loosen up the individual transplant without damaging them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/loosing-up-the-transplants-with-a-dibble-plate.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/loosing-up-the-transplants-with-a-dibble-plate_huf5d2df61c44b73ed0316e7353de7655d_142826_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/loosing-up-the-transplants-with-a-dibble-plate_huf5d2df61c44b73ed0316e7353de7655d_142826_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/loosing-up-the-transplants-with-a-dibble-plate_huf5d2df61c44b73ed0316e7353de7655d_142826_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Loosing up the transplants with a dibble plate"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, you will simply lay at each intersection of the grid you drew earlier one transplant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-lays-down-one-transplant-at-each-intersection-of-the-grid.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_huf2efb6024a4dcd40c9819d9260fc1245_216062_8cb1759d7b24b0c54b9348984463c716.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_huf2efb6024a4dcd40c9819d9260fc1245_216062_8c180e38ff990921a31bb1fb7f1f8470.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/_huf2efb6024a4dcd40c9819d9260fc1245_216062_6764d8461a8ed34669e132689664a1e4.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A man lying down one transplant at each intersection of the grid"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="To keep your strength and health" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">To keep your strength and health&lt;/p>&lt;p>Either:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>work on your knees&lt;/li>
&lt;li>work with your legs bent&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>But refrain from standing up and bending down as it will kill your back over time…&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Finally, the transplanting is straight forward: since the soil is loose, you simply put 2 fingers in it to make a little hole in which to plant the transplant. Finish with ferming the soil around it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvesting-the-winter-crops">Harvesting the winter crops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Again, always work on your knees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s take the example of turnips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, if the weather is warm in the early spring, then flea beetles may infect your crops. This is why neeting with a fleece can become important, especially for turnips that are a profitable crop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-leaves-from-flea-beetles.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-leaves-from-flea-beetles_hu9db7f4e9f8b1ffab5793479728d51598_149894_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-leaves-from-flea-beetles_hu9db7f4e9f8b1ffab5793479728d51598_149894_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-leaves-from-flea-beetles_hu9db7f4e9f8b1ffab5793479728d51598_149894_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Damaged leaves from flea beetles"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flea beetle’s attacks can decrease the photosynthesis and stress the plant resulting in a poor quality turnip.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you sell turnips with the leaves, it could turn away the customers with damaged leaves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So always grow turnips with a fleece cover.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno uses simple elastic to bundle up 3 to 5 turnips together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cleaning up the yellow leaves is a good idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any turnip that is too small, chicken will love the snack :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the turnips are bundled, you will need to wash them and control the quality. In fact, besides the flea beetle, root maggots are another pest that can damage the root vegetables from the ground.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-turnip-by-a-root-maggot.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-turnip-by-a-root-maggot_hu03e7c4ab5326dcc827ea1825d479d459_118554_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-turnip-by-a-root-maggot_hu03e7c4ab5326dcc827ea1825d479d459_118554_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-04/market-gardening-in-april-the-dutch-farmer/images/damaged-turnip-by-a-root-maggot_hu03e7c4ab5326dcc827ea1825d479d459_118554_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Damaged turnip by a root maggot"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It makes the sale of turnips impossible when they are damaged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In early spring, this is when the adult flies lay eggs and the larvas go into the soil to develop and eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="What can you do without using chemicals?" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">What can you do without using chemicals?&lt;/p>&lt;p>Using a netting, rotating the crops and keeping your soil healthy will help to keep the turnips healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And remember, even the organically approved chemicals are just as bad as conventionnal ones!&lt;/p>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in March, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/2023-03-06-a-man-in-a-garden-sowing-seed-on-a-garden-bed.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Market Gardening in March, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>Spring is here and a lot is happening in the garden: bees are at work, sowing new crops is the main job and overwinters crops are still producing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xILmYuRdjUM">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overwinter-crops">Overwinter crops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Moreno planted spinach in September and they’re really taking off at this time of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/moreno-is-explaining-how-spinach-is-a-great-crop-for-the-end-of-winter-and-beginning-of-spring.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu3b6a8e19cef3d476aba1ca360b9fcee8_200545_8777a6ce9f87090a3ca03d0f85de87fa.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu3b6a8e19cef3d476aba1ca360b9fcee8_200545_60f9e79b702d30b59e17d52ff4e068d3.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/_hu3b6a8e19cef3d476aba1ca360b9fcee8_200545_146c92bb3383c605cf737d6181420564.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Moreno is explaining how spinach is a great crop for the end of winter and the beginning of spring"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another crop that could work if it survives the winter is green onions. It’s planted at the same time of spinach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, winter carrots are ready for harvest and, in market gardening, it’s a great thing to have organically grown carrots in March.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-can-we-plant-now-in-march">What can we plant now, in March&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="aspargus-and-strawberries">Aspargus and strawberries&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>They’re crops that you can plant now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno is planting them between a &lt;em>fence&lt;/em> of garlic: the strawberries between every 2 garlic and the asparagus in the middle of the row, as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bed-for-perrenial-crops-in-between-2-rows-of-garlic.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bed-for-perrenial-crops-in-between-2-rows-of-garlic_hu69fe146df8ccf4c682d604a729866e12_223747_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bed-for-perrenial-crops-in-between-2-rows-of-garlic_hu69fe146df8ccf4c682d604a729866e12_223747_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bed-for-perrenial-crops-in-between-2-rows-of-garlic_hu69fe146df8ccf4c682d604a729866e12_223747_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bed for perennial crops in between 2 rows of garlic"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>What I have found about the Alium family is that it’s a great repellant for slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I planted my strawberries in the fall of this year, at the same time as the garlic &lt;em>protecting&lt;/em> them.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="peas">Peas&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>They can withstand up to -6 °C so they’re a great crop to plant now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a crop on the low end of the profitability scale. However, it can offer diversity to the farmer’s customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create the peas’ fence, Moreno uses:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>wooden poles spaced by 1.8 m&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a simple net with a large-sized mesh&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Then he applies the same amount of compost (2–3 cm thick) in a narrow row and sows the seeds about 3–4 cm apart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/grown-up-peas.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/grown-up-peas_hu994df6eccc612c58168964b852a58b6e_194718_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/grown-up-peas_hu994df6eccc612c58168964b852a58b6e_194718_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/grown-up-peas_hu994df6eccc612c58168964b852a58b6e_194718_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Grown up peas"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peas grow vertically: this is a very good thing when you have limited garden space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of that we easily add lettuces, arugulas, beets or carrots at the base of the peas. In fact, the crops won’t compete for sunlight and you will get more out of the small area.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overstory-trees">Overstory trees&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-tree-blooming-in-march.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-tree-blooming-in-march_hud41a496d7ec472805ac0cef405304f59_124445_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-tree-blooming-in-march_hud41a496d7ec472805ac0cef405304f59_124445_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-tree-blooming-in-march_hud41a496d7ec472805ac0cef405304f59_124445_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A tree blooming in March"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees are a vital participant in a farmer’s garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How is that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They consume the carbon dioxide of the air through the photosynthesis and transform it into a carbon that will feed the soil and its life. They attract a wide variety of fungi and bacteria. They in turn feed on the elements given by the tree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In return, they give away nutrients that the soil life will consume. Finally, the soil life produces the food for the crops that produce our food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tree and their root system can hold 10 times more water than soil with no organic matter. It’s really something to take care of because water is a really precious resource.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working with the soil lifecycle, introducing perennial plants and trees is a key way to make sure we can survive on the Earth and take care of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another factor in favor of this is the diversity it brings to the garden. Compared to a single crop field, grown on bare soil, do we see the difference?&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>How do I plan for a sustainable garden?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have added about 10 cm to 15 cm of autumn leaves on all the beds in November and December.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday, while planting the potatoes under that blanket of leaves, I could see the moisture about 5 cm down. That is really nice when you know we had a month of January that is the the driest in a long time (no rain in more than 30 days).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In early 2023, we’re already seen warning of a serious drought. Covering the beds adds resilience to the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe we may grow more on highly industrialized farms, what about the quality and the sustainability of such methods?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aren&amp;rsquo;t respectful gardening techniques more profitable in the long term even if yields are lower?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>==Thinking about it before buying your next carrots from your supermarket or the tomatoes that shouldn’t be available at this time.==&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>See the detailed explanation and point of view from Moreno at &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xILmYuRdjUM?t=490">8:10 to 11:00&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="experimentations">Experimentations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It allows creative thinking is a key to success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno is trying out turmeric and ginger!&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I’ve been wanting to try this also! Let’s see how Moreno goes about it.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>First, start small when experimenting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>buy clean and mold-free rhizomes from a local organic shop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut them in 4 cm to 5 cm long pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>let the piece to &lt;em>heal&lt;/em> from the cut for 2 to 3 days.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>soak the pieces in water to speed up the germination.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>plant pieces of turmeric or ginger in compost.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/ginger-root-is-a-tray-filled-with-compost.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/ginger-root-is-a-tray-filled-with-compost_hu3df824eb83e8d09c5ba2ea3b7679cf76_150651_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/ginger-root-is-a-tray-filled-with-compost_hu3df824eb83e8d09c5ba2ea3b7679cf76_150651_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/ginger-root-is-a-tray-filled-with-compost_hu3df824eb83e8d09c5ba2ea3b7679cf76_150651_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ginger root is a tray filled with compost"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The germination can take a few weeks up to a few months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s important to keep those tropical plants at 20 °C minimum so they can grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indoor is usually a good place to start growing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the leaves start to appear, you will be able to move them outside under cover.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="seeding">Seeding&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/several-trays-of-lettuces.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/several-trays-of-lettuces_hu16835998d8279fdbce0731580d4dbd24_181873_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/several-trays-of-lettuces_hu16835998d8279fdbce0731580d4dbd24_181873_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/several-trays-of-lettuces_hu16835998d8279fdbce0731580d4dbd24_181873_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Several trays of lettuces"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How does Moreno go about seeding in trays?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He uses the 2 cm wide trays as shown above the lettuces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For other crops requiring more root space, he uses the regular sized pots as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/regular-seeding-pots-for-larger-roots.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/regular-seeding-pots-for-larger-roots_hu5d6a5a65c6645480be02436132c0596a_153860_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/regular-seeding-pots-for-larger-roots_hu5d6a5a65c6645480be02436132c0596a_153860_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/regular-seeding-pots-for-larger-roots_hu5d6a5a65c6645480be02436132c0596a_153860_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Regular seeding pots for larger roots"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="prepare-the-potting-mix">Prepare the potting mix&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Water it so it’s moist but not wet. See Moreno showing the squeeze technique &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xILmYuRdjUM?t=991">from minute 16:31&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="filling-the-tray">Filling the tray&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/large-tray-of-2-cm-hole-filled-with-potting-mix.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/large-tray-of-2-cm-hole-filled-with-potting-mix_hu61d5dc0c9bcae5ea16d30164d7e20a1c_175510_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/large-tray-of-2-cm-hole-filled-with-potting-mix_hu61d5dc0c9bcae5ea16d30164d7e20a1c_175510_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/large-tray-of-2-cm-hole-filled-with-potting-mix_hu61d5dc0c9bcae5ea16d30164d7e20a1c_175510_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Large tray of 2 cm hole filled with potting mix"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="Make to double-check the filling of the side and corner hole." >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Make to double-check the filling of the side and corner hole.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Once filled, lift and drop from a 25 cm height the tray to compact slightly the medium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complete the filling of the holes where necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="seeding-the-seeds">Seeding the seeds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Use your fingers or a little pointy tool to create a small depression on the compost mix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The depth depends on the crops, but usually, for lettuce, 1 cm or 2 cm will suffice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, sow individually the seeds, add another layer of compost mix to cover the seeds and water a little again.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="Label it and date it" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Label it and date it&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I use a GLORIA Hobby 100 Pressure Sprayer (available &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3HDhcaX">in France&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3PtT1xK">in the UK&lt;/a>; &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3HGzSH5">in the US&lt;/a>, this brand doesn’t seem to be available.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s quite handy as you can adjust the spray finely. Also, it’s sturdier than a bigger version sprayer (not the same brand) of 5 liters capacity. It broke twice after a year :( So I recommend a 1 liter like this Gloria model.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="composting">Composting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/rooster-and-hens-eating-fresh-compost.jpg"
width="600"
height="312"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/rooster-and-hens-eating-fresh-compost_hubf60517c9519a4a77333940c3151f8d2_197858_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/rooster-and-hens-eating-fresh-compost_hubf60517c9519a4a77333940c3151f8d2_197858_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/rooster-and-hens-eating-fresh-compost_hubf60517c9519a4a77333940c3151f8d2_197858_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rooster and hens eating fresh compost"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="461px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laying the fresh compost directly on the beds in France isn’t a good idea because it can become a perfect slug habitat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, instead, if you can have chicken, feed them with your compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will provide fertilizing matter and eggs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/5-eggs-ready-to-pick.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/5-eggs-ready-to-pick_hu2002bb23adfe2f8eb9e605f3aba14c97_201429_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/5-eggs-ready-to-pick_hu2002bb23adfe2f8eb9e605f3aba14c97_201429_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/5-eggs-ready-to-pick_hu2002bb23adfe2f8eb9e605f3aba14c97_201429_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="5 eggs ready to pick"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno uses a 3-section compost pile to use the chicken’s work to enrich the compost and produce an aerobic compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>He sets the fresher material in section 1 and let the chicken work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then he moves the pile to the section 2 when the pile shows advanced decomposition
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the section 2, the chicken will continue their job and the bacteria and fungi will multiply&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, he moves to the section 3 to let the compost finish.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/3-sections-chicken-compost-pile.jpg"
width="600"
height="334"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/3-sections-chicken-compost-pile_huc5b97612330b3f21f4aadc493ea05101_158071_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/3-sections-chicken-compost-pile_huc5b97612330b3f21f4aadc493ea05101_158071_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-03/market-gardening-in-march-the-dutch-farmer/images/3-sections-chicken-compost-pile_huc5b97612330b3f21f4aadc493ea05101_158071_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="3-section chicken compost pile"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="179"
data-flex-basis="431px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a great to go from:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>waste to crop production&lt;/li>
&lt;li>waste to egg production&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>You can make all your own compost yourself? Yes, but it will require time and a lot of energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The compost need of garden is pretty important and even if you’re quite fit, don’t you need to keep some energy for more important tasks when you could get cheap compost locally?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look at the place around, ask small businesses selling plants and trees. They may know where to find good compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno buys his high-quality compost at 10 euros a cubic meter. To produce himself a cube meter of finished compost, it would require 12 hours of work [3 turning of 4h for a pile of 5 cube meters at the start].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even at a 15 euros per hour labor cost, you can see that the sustainability of producing compost yourself is simply not profitable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Companies specialize in producing good compost. Perform a cost analysis before diving into making your own compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may be surprised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, you should make some of your own compost. Simply find the best balance between making it and buying it.&lt;/p>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Market Gardening in February, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>What was true in January is still applicable in February. However, during the month of February, we’re seen at the end of the winter&amp;rsquo;s tunnel. Moreno will go into more depth about Market Gardening for this month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KB7mGo8RY2k">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="keep-on-propagating-and-planting-shrubs-and-flowers">Keep on propagating and planting shrubs and flowers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/propagating-sage-rosemary-and-thyme.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/propagating-sage-rosemary-and-thyme_hu5328c9eb82a5fef9000bb0ee3a85ddee_202284_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/propagating-sage-rosemary-and-thyme_hu5328c9eb82a5fef9000bb0ee3a85ddee_202284_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/propagating-sage-rosemary-and-thyme_hu5328c9eb82a5fef9000bb0ee3a85ddee_202284_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Propagating sage, rosemary and thyme"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We should continue to propagate the shrubs and aromatic plants to multiply them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, if you can afford to buy and plant flower bulbs to increase the diversity on the farm, go for it!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="crop-planting-plan">Crop planting plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now is the time to complete the plan for the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will need to organize the seeds, the tools to be ready when the sowing and planting will start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That includes finishing the last cleaning of garden space so they’re all ready to receive the crops.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvest-of-winter-crops">Harvest of winter crops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you did plant winter crops, you will continue getting the crops, weather-permitting, of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, what you planted in August and September last year could still be available for sale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2023-02-07-kale-in-february.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Kale in February"
>
Let&amp;rsquo;s take kale: in February, it’s still producing and it’s a hardy (meaning resistant) and it’s the most profitable crop at this time of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unless you live in a cold climate, where you will need a greenhouse or a polytunnel, then you go for kale next season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And even if you live in a colder climate, using fleeces (white cover sheet) you can add protection so the crops perform better.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="Be careful of damage to the fleeces" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Be careful of damage to the fleeces&lt;/p>&lt;p>In fact, if your beds are positioned under trees, the falling branches can damage the fleece that is actually no thicker than toilet paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my experience, I think it also depends on the quality of the fleece. I personally use &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3Cwfuoo">this fleece for Winter Garden cover&lt;/a> which I bought already 2 years ago and this year. It holds very well over time.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the vlog, Moreno harvests carrots sowed during the previous summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="working-with-the-birth-death-cycle-of-nature">Working with the birth-death cycle of nature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a farmer, you work to extract the most nutrient out of the soil to grow annual crops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In nature, the ecosystem would look like what you see in a forest, with trees and perennials. It’s self-sustaining.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/mushrooms.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/mushrooms_hu57d823b19429fb16a0f1a68a973d0fa1_109346_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/mushrooms_hu57d823b19429fb16a0f1a68a973d0fa1_109346_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/mushrooms_hu57d823b19429fb16a0f1a68a973d0fa1_109346_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Mushrooms"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of our jobs as annual vegetables grower is to bring fertility to our land so we’re as close as possible to the natural cycle. This is a key way to continue getting predictable and quality yields year after year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-does-work">How does work&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After harvesting the remaining crops and tidying up the beds, you apply a 5 cm layer of compost evenly.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="About not enough broken-down compost" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">About not enough broken-down compost&lt;/p>&lt;p>Moreno showcases a non-mature compost in the vlog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It contains quite a lot of wood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It isn’t a problem &lt;strong>as long as it isn’t tilled into the soil&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you apply it on the surface, the roots will go down below that compost while it finishes breaking-down.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-young-calf.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-young-calf_hua98f987375b0718c81ff3eee9da6d99a_93101_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-young-calf_hua98f987375b0718c81ff3eee9da6d99a_93101_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-young-calf_hua98f987375b0718c81ff3eee9da6d99a_93101_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A calf"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using a one-year-old cow manure compost would be much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Moreno, he made a deal with a local farmer owing cows. The farmer sets aside a big pile of cow manure for a year and using a aerating machine, he breaks down the manure into a perfect compost for market gardening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you applied the compost, you can also firm up the layer with a nice little tool called &lt;em>a bed roller&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-roller-like-tool-to-firm-used-to-firm-up-the-compost.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-roller-like-tool-to-firm-used-to-firm-up-the-compost_hu9c422978a41b8fe1bbc5029600e6aade_207616_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-roller-like-tool-to-firm-used-to-firm-up-the-compost_hu9c422978a41b8fe1bbc5029600e6aade_207616_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-roller-like-tool-to-firm-used-to-firm-up-the-compost_hu9c422978a41b8fe1bbc5029600e6aade_207616_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="a roller-like tool to firm up the compost"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more details about low-cost tools for market gardening, check out &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yUFr0C1FJjE">this vlog from Moreno&lt;/a> which I will cover someday.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="clean-pathways-with-woodchips">Clean pathways with woodchips&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/woodchips-on-a-pathway.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/woodchips-on-a-pathway_hu05aa60e2bfa2364b3a0109375aa63461_234746_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/woodchips-on-a-pathway_hu05aa60e2bfa2364b3a0109375aa63461_234746_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/woodchips-on-a-pathway_hu05aa60e2bfa2364b3a0109375aa63461_234746_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Woodchips on a pathway"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woodchip serves 2 roles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>creating clean and tidy pathways&lt;/li>
&lt;li>feeding the soil as it starts to break down.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It’s an amazing added element to the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It acts as a sponge for an excess of water and it brings fungi that are an important ingredient to good soil life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way, it’s like adding a blanket to the soil, protecting the soil underneath from the weather.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, you barely get dirty boots with a woodchip-covered pathway 🌟.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It isn’t a must to apply woodchips, but you have them available for free or a small cost, definitely use them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="direct-sowing-in-february">Direct sowing in February&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="Be careful: winter ain&amp;#39;t over!" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Be careful: winter ain&amp;#39;t over!&lt;/p>&lt;p>It will depend on where you live, but in a 7B climate, you can still get frost up the first week of May.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It would be a shame to lose early-sowed crops in one cold night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check out the gardening climate using &lt;a href="https://www.gardenia.net/guide/european-hardiness-zones">this link from Gardenia.net&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>So what can you plant?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno lives in a 7B climate zone and will direct sow:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>arugula&lt;/li>
&lt;li>radishes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>turnips&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mustards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>kale&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Undercover, you can also plant beets and carrots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an unheated polytunnel, you can also start seedlings for other crops for the Brassicaceae family like cauliflower, broccoli, cabbages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lettuces, fennel or some Swiss shards are also crops you can start seedlings for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, for slow-growing plants, like peppers and eggplants, they need a lot more time to getting start and therefore they will need heat. February is the perfect time to start them if you can afford the cost of heating mat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, count the cost: is it worth the money to grow from scratch those vegetables as you will need to allocate a cozy and protected place in your home?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have a local farmer handling large number of seedlings for those crops? Maybe prefer buying your plants from him instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="using-a-jang-seeder-for-arugula">Using a jang seeder for arugula&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The jang seeder is a great tool to sow large number of seeds when working on a market garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/jang-seeder.jpg"
width="600"
height="383"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/jang-seeder_hu7e45d81c45c9cf494df0b56f772bf5cf_72248_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/jang-seeder_hu7e45d81c45c9cf494df0b56f772bf5cf_72248_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/jang-seeder_hu7e45d81c45c9cf494df0b56f772bf5cf_72248_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A jang seeder"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="156"
data-flex-basis="375px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to follow a couple of important steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pick the right roller for the seeds to plant.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For arugula, you will need the &lt;em>YYG24&lt;/em> plate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/seeding-plates-of-jang-seeder.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/seeding-plates-of-jang-seeder_huc5bce157394f93b9628e52cbbfe8829e_92738_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/seeding-plates-of-jang-seeder_huc5bce157394f93b9628e52cbbfe8829e_92738_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/seeding-plates-of-jang-seeder_huc5bce157394f93b9628e52cbbfe8829e_92738_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Seeding plates of jang seeder"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>install the plate into the hopper, which is the case that holds the seeds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>weight the seeds you use to plant the beds to calculate the production cost of the bed and the crop.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>keeping a spreadsheet to record what you use and produce is important for a sustainable market garden. See &lt;a href="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/#work-on-projects-and-planning">the previous post for details&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To choose the density of sowing for arugula, you will need to choose your goal:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>if you need to grow small leaves, then go for a high density (the 6-row seeder is then a better-suited tool)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if you need to grow larger leaves, then the jang seeder is used.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After sowing, place a fleece into the top of small steel wire hoofs&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/steel-wire-hoofs.jpg"
width="600"
height="293"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/steel-wire-hoofs_hudfa18c44e85536828da7b2ef9da67cb7_221826_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/steel-wire-hoofs_hudfa18c44e85536828da7b2ef9da67cb7_221826_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/steel-wire-hoofs_hudfa18c44e85536828da7b2ef9da67cb7_221826_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Steel-wire hoofs"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="204"
data-flex-basis="491px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/fleece-on-the-steel-hoofs.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/fleece-on-the-steel-hoofs_hu512c767869f061be6d124ac3c2a7e2bf_175093_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/fleece-on-the-steel-hoofs_hu512c767869f061be6d124ac3c2a7e2bf_175093_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-02/market-gardening-in-february-the-dutch-farmer/images/fleece-on-the-steel-hoofs_hu512c767869f061be6d124ac3c2a7e2bf_175093_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Fleece on the steel hoofs"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-warning" id="Hard frost" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Hard frost&lt;/p>&lt;p>A very hard frost can kill the seeds even with the fleece. You take a risk by seeding now.&lt;/p>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>A Day in The Life of a Farmer in January, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>What does a day in January look like? The Dutch Farmer will detail it to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ScBleHwOkgA">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Wood burning in a stove"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a slow and relax month when we can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>reflect on the past year,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>analyze the data from the past year of harvest,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and plan accordingly for the coming year.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The days are gray usually in January but the days are lengthening and that means more sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if January is a slow and relax month, you can still do a lot in the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvest-of-the-remaining-crops">Harvest of the remaining crops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this time of the year (and in the south of France as it’s where Moreno shot this vlog), you can still have the following crops to harvest:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>kale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Swiss chard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Winter carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="cleaning">Cleaning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Also, anything not harvested, or that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it with the first frost, needs to be cleaned up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use those wastes for the next compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, you can give away those old crops to the chicken if you have any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Chicken feasting on old lettuces"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, you finish preparing the beds with a fresh layer ready compost to fertilize the soil for spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversify-the-farms-income-streams">Diversify the farm&amp;rsquo;s income streams&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To create a resilient farm, you need multiple income streams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it include?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>producing various types of crops to sell on markets&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>dedicate an area to perennials and create a plant nursery:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>including berries like currants, black berries&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Black berry fruits"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>and medicinal plants like rosemary, thyme, lavender and sage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Lavender"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>sell vegetable transplants for the community&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>produce microgreens&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>grow mushrooms if you have the place and resources for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="small-farm-market-gardening-a-good-business">Small farm market gardening: a good business&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The initial investment is relatively low compared to the traditional farming process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno made &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yUFr0C1FJjE">a vlog about the tools you need to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s possible to do such an activity on a rented land.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, producing various types of crops to sell on markets is the first income stream and the first goal to start a farming business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to focus and give everything within your abilities to make this business functional as soon as possible. Once you reach the functional stage, then you can venture out into creating other income streams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start to make a living then play around and experiment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno transformed a very grassy land into a very productive farm using no dig. He details &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g2DDQ-uuLl0">the process in this vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pruning-trees-and-bushes">Pruning trees and bushes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clearing bushes will give the plant the opportunity to give new growth as the spring arrives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pruning trees will provide more energy to the branches you need to keep produce the next year&amp;rsquo;s fruits. Those branches will bloom with new flowers and leaves more efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, cleaning the garden, especially bushes, makes it less inviting to the slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="increase-biodiversity">Increase biodiversity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If your soil isn’t frozen, plant bulb flowers, like tulips and amaryllis, that will provide beauty in the garden and early food to the pollinators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a long winter, it’s very nice to hear the bees buzzing on the first flowers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bee on a pink flower"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s our job as caretakers of the land we use to provide food sources to the wildlife.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another example is to hang up bird feeders and housing for them as they’re your allies to eat the insects you want them to take of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your land is welcoming, wildlife will come to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="propagate-shrubs">Propagate shrubs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When they lose their leaves, the shrubs become dormant until spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can then multiply them using the cutting or division technique.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Either way, you prune a branch of what you want to multiply. You should prune a pencil-thick branch so it can work successfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, cut them into 10 cm to 25 cm pieces before placing them in pots filled with compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This technique works great for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>roses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blackcurrants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>redcurrants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blackberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grapes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>figs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For example, Morena once created 7 new trees from a single branch. Similarly with 2 blackcurrant stalks, he creates 10 new blackcurrant plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another multiplication that you can do is dividing a root into several pieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, with rhubarb, you create 12 new plants with one mother root. You just need to make sure each piece contains a crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure I will find a vlog that explains this in detail.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="early-sowing">Early sowing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do this only if you have a polytunnel or a greenhouse to start sowing lettuces or spinach, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, you should wait until March.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work-on-projects-and-planning">Work on projects and planning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since the garden needs less time from you, you can design, build or repair what you need for the coming year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Planning is crucial so you have enough seeds to create seedlings that will produce the vegetables to sell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The technique is to start with the goal in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much do you need to earn to live your chosen lifestyle, pay the bills and save. Moreno goes into more details &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRlUhUWS0Hk">on this vlog untitled &lt;em>How to Start a Farm From Scratch (Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Growing Vegetables for Profit)&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, stay tuned as I take more notes about Moreno and his vlog on his Dutch Farmer channel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Plant Garlic From Start to Finish, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-09-29-a-garlic-and-some-cloves.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to Plant Garlic From Start to Finish, by The Dutch Farmer" />&lt;p>Step by step, Moreno shows how to plant this crop successfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Thanks to The Dutch Farmer for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer&amp;rsquo;s channel. You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BNR8b4_o2LA">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="times">Times&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="september-preparing-the-cloves">September: preparing the cloves&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/september-preparing-many-cloves.jpg"
width="600"
height="312"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/september-preparing-many-cloves_hu480c3c3e5bb68aa0b1f137a863f7add6_151455_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/september-preparing-many-cloves_hu480c3c3e5bb68aa0b1f137a863f7add6_151455_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/september-preparing-many-cloves_hu480c3c3e5bb68aa0b1f137a863f7add6_151455_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Breaking down last year&amp;rsquo;s garlic heads"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="461px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From your best garlic heads from last harvest (or &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/supermarket-garlic-for-seed-charles-dowding/">from your organic store&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>), break down the garlic into individual cloves.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="october-25-planting">October 25: planting&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Prepare the soil in no dig. Below, bulk compost is used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting_hub9a7ab554d1710c8c21bda3232ff69af_222849_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting_hub9a7ab554d1710c8c21bda3232ff69af_222849_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting_hub9a7ab554d1710c8c21bda3232ff69af_222849_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Setup garlic on mulch"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Space the cloves 5 cm to 10 cm from each other in rows of about 30 cm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting-details.jpg"
width="600"
height="314"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting-details_hu2c9ab561bc64a3fa57f8404fdecd2dcd_221346_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting-details_hu2c9ab561bc64a3fa57f8404fdecd2dcd_221346_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/october-25-planting-details_hu2c9ab561bc64a3fa57f8404fdecd2dcd_221346_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Space the cloves 5 cm to 10 cm from each other in rows of about 30 cm"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="191"
data-flex-basis="458px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Credits: image taken from The Dutch Farmer&amp;rsquo;s vlog.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="march-17-new-garlic-has-come-out">March 17: new garlic has come out&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/march-17-young-garlic.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/march-17-young-garlic_hu4d8cb3044055408cbc95a66e9511564d_177094_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/march-17-young-garlic_hu4d8cb3044055408cbc95a66e9511564d_177094_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/march-17-young-garlic_hu4d8cb3044055408cbc95a66e9511564d_177094_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The new garlic is out"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="may-21st-garlic-is-at-adult-size">May 21st: garlic is at adult size&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/may-21-adult-garlic.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/may-21-adult-garlic_hu6b4bde53d740fe0100dc540307afbb31_237412_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/may-21-adult-garlic_hu6b4bde53d740fe0100dc540307afbb31_237412_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/may-21-adult-garlic_hu6b4bde53d740fe0100dc540307afbb31_237412_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Garlic has grown to adult size"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="june-27th-harvest-and-set-to-dry">June 27th: harvest and set to dry&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Around the beginning of the summer (end of June in the northern atmosphere), the garlic should be ready to harvest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-judge-the-readiness-of-garlic-charles-dowding/">how to judge the readiness of garlic&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-harvest.jpg"
width="600"
height="306"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-harvest_hub906cde2083333271fba50f1195b5ca2_226542_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-harvest_hub906cde2083333271fba50f1195b5ca2_226542_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-harvest_hub906cde2083333271fba50f1195b5ca2_226542_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Harvesting garlic"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="196"
data-flex-basis="470px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, set it put to dry under cover by hanging the garlic:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-setup-to-dry.jpg"
width="600"
height="323"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-setup-to-dry_hu56b7e18afd1cd7130da73b31f1b2087e_197264_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-setup-to-dry_hu56b7e18afd1cd7130da73b31f1b2087e_197264_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/june-27-setup-to-dry_hu56b7e18afd1cd7130da73b31f1b2087e_197264_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Setup garlic to dry"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="185"
data-flex-basis="445px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="august-29th-garlic-is-ready">August 29th: garlic is ready&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>About 2 months later, garlic is dried &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/august-29-dried-garlic.jpg"
width="600"
height="307"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/august-29-dried-garlic_huc6c31345e2ee50a56f1f6aabcbb146f0_191259_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/august-29-dried-garlic_huc6c31345e2ee50a56f1f6aabcbb146f0_191259_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/august-29-dried-garlic_huc6c31345e2ee50a56f1f6aabcbb146f0_191259_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Dried garlic"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="195"
data-flex-basis="469px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="august-30th-prepare-for-storage">August 30th: prepare for storage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; and it is ready to be stored for later consumption or soon coming new planting season!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You simply cut off the dried stem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/augsut-30-ready-to-store.jpg"
width="600"
height="304"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/augsut-30-ready-to-store_hu1d425a51dcf3e9251edc1941b4d45468_151040_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/augsut-30-ready-to-store_hu1d425a51dcf3e9251edc1941b4d45468_151040_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-09/how-to-plant-garlic-start-to-finish-the-dutch-farmer/images/augsut-30-ready-to-store_hu1d425a51dcf3e9251edc1941b4d45468_151040_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Store garlic by cutting the stem"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="197"
data-flex-basis="473px"
>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>