<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>In January on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-january/</link><description>Recent content in In January on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-january/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Day in The Life of a Farmer in January, by The Dutch Farmer</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>What does a day in January look like? The Dutch Farmer will detail it to us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Moreno for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on The Dutch Farmer’s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ScBleHwOkgA">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/wood-burning-in-a-stove_huc1672ee02c6dfb4223776e05a241eb3b_132828_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Wood burning in a stove"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a slow and relax month when we can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>reflect on the past year,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>analyze the data from the past year of harvest,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and plan accordingly for the coming year.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The days are gray usually in January but the days are lengthening and that means more sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if January is a slow and relax month, you can still do a lot in the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="harvest-of-the-remaining-crops">Harvest of the remaining crops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this time of the year (and in the south of France as it’s where Moreno shot this vlog), you can still have the following crops to harvest:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>kale&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Swiss chard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In Winter carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="cleaning">Cleaning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Also, anything not harvested, or that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it with the first frost, needs to be cleaned up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use those wastes for the next compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, you can give away those old crops to the chicken if you have any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces.jpg"
width="600"
height="308"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/chicken-feasting-on-old-lettuces_hu9dc6c14dabec581fa1ad47f6ac3df388_233132_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Chicken feasting on old lettuces"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="467px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, you finish preparing the beds with a fresh layer ready compost to fertilize the soil for spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversify-the-farms-income-streams">Diversify the farm&amp;rsquo;s income streams&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To create a resilient farm, you need multiple income streams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it include?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>producing various types of crops to sell on markets&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>dedicate an area to perennials and create a plant nursery:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>including berries like currants, black berries&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/black-berries_hu723edc16f4664e16b15c3de0b5c1bbde_126037_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Black berry fruits"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>and medicinal plants like rosemary, thyme, lavender and sage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/lavender_hu73d29a3246f1df71db32315c24cbd086_136056_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Lavender"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>sell vegetable transplants for the community&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>produce microgreens&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>grow mushrooms if you have the place and resources for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="small-farm-market-gardening-a-good-business">Small farm market gardening: a good business&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The initial investment is relatively low compared to the traditional farming process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno made &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yUFr0C1FJjE">a vlog about the tools you need to get started&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s possible to do such an activity on a rented land.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, producing various types of crops to sell on markets is the first income stream and the first goal to start a farming business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to focus and give everything within your abilities to make this business functional as soon as possible. Once you reach the functional stage, then you can venture out into creating other income streams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start to make a living then play around and experiment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreno transformed a very grassy land into a very productive farm using no dig. He details &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g2DDQ-uuLl0">the process in this vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pruning-trees-and-bushes">Pruning trees and bushes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clearing bushes will give the plant the opportunity to give new growth as the spring arrives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pruning trees will provide more energy to the branches you need to keep produce the next year&amp;rsquo;s fruits. Those branches will bloom with new flowers and leaves more efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, cleaning the garden, especially bushes, makes it less inviting to the slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="increase-biodiversity">Increase biodiversity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If your soil isn’t frozen, plant bulb flowers, like tulips and amaryllis, that will provide beauty in the garden and early food to the pollinators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a long winter, it’s very nice to hear the bees buzzing on the first flowers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower.jpg"
width="600"
height="310"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/market-gardening-in-january-the-dutch-farmer/images/a-bee-n-a-pink-flower_hu3fde01346f957c75795ecb36c2876b26_119406_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bee on a pink flower"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="193"
data-flex-basis="464px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s our job as caretakers of the land we use to provide food sources to the wildlife.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another example is to hang up bird feeders and housing for them as they’re your allies to eat the insects you want them to take of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your land is welcoming, wildlife will come to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="propagate-shrubs">Propagate shrubs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When they lose their leaves, the shrubs become dormant until spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can then multiply them using the cutting or division technique.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Either way, you prune a branch of what you want to multiply. You should prune a pencil-thick branch so it can work successfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, cut them into 10 cm to 25 cm pieces before placing them in pots filled with compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This technique works great for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>roses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blackcurrants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>redcurrants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blackberries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grapes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>figs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For example, Morena once created 7 new trees from a single branch. Similarly with 2 blackcurrant stalks, he creates 10 new blackcurrant plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another multiplication that you can do is dividing a root into several pieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, with rhubarb, you create 12 new plants with one mother root. You just need to make sure each piece contains a crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure I will find a vlog that explains this in detail.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="early-sowing">Early sowing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do this only if you have a polytunnel or a greenhouse to start sowing lettuces or spinach, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, you should wait until March.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="work-on-projects-and-planning">Work on projects and planning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since the garden needs less time from you, you can design, build or repair what you need for the coming year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Planning is crucial so you have enough seeds to create seedlings that will produce the vegetables to sell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The technique is to start with the goal in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much do you need to earn to live your chosen lifestyle, pay the bills and save. Moreno goes into more details &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRlUhUWS0Hk">on this vlog untitled &lt;em>How to Start a Farm From Scratch (Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Growing Vegetables for Profit)&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, stay tuned as I take more notes about Moreno and his vlog on his Dutch Farmer channel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I Love January as a Gardener, by Huw Richards</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/why-i-love-january-as-a-gardener-huw-richards/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/why-i-love-january-as-a-gardener-huw-richards/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2023-01-12-huw-garden-in-january-2022.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Huw’s garden in January 2022"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In January, we don’t like going outside because it’s cozy inside. But, maybe, you’re like Huw and, in reality, you need to do some work in the garden. Let’s what&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Huw Richards for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Huw Richards’ channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g4Weoqv6D6Y">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="january-is-a-synonym-to-preparation">January is a synonym to preparation.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For example, you can start with spreading a load of compost on the beds where you don’t still have food growing, like cabbages or Swiss chard, very useful for the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hungry_gap">Hungry Gap&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you tidy your garden, you can reflect on the past year and find out what your plan will look like for the year to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, you don’t want to change your raised beds in the spring but during those winter months.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Using a tarmac rake" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Using a tarmac rake&lt;/p>&lt;p>Those rakes are heavier than the normal rake because of their end use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For spreading compost, they’re also great to help us spread up the compost.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Huw thinks that you need to apply a 5 cm to 7 cm compost layer on the raised beds yearly to replenish the nutrient content of the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>To put this in concrete numbers, a 5 cm layer of compost on a bed 100 m² garden (which is useable for the crops and excluding the alleys), you would need 5 metrics cube of compost or 5000 liters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where I live, to get that much compost would cost a fortune. At 10 euros a bag of 70 liters, it would cost 714 euros to cover the beds…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are places where you can find compost in bulk for a lower price. In my case, I can’t have it delivered because the minimum quantity is 10 tons!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could go rent a truck to hold about one ton, equivalent to 2000 liters, for about 115 euros (of which the compost costs just 26…).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting compost when you start feels like a challenge!&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The when to put the compost depends on what you will grow. In general you will apply compost between autumn and winter. However, you will apply it also in the summer for the Brassicaceae.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="january-is-about-planning">January is about planning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It’s a simple month but it’s a key one.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use the time to plan what you will grow, where, with what other crops.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use the past year’s experience to adjust what didn’t work to try out something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Personal note" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Personal note&lt;/p>&lt;p>I have a lot of ideas and I’m currently writing a journal of all I will do in the 2022–2023 year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me a year begins with autumn harvest time is over until the next one. So it falls around October.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, in summary, I picked up a lot of leaves from a nearby park (about 12 metric cubes) to not only cover my garden with &lt;em>a keep-warm blanket&lt;/em> but also make more compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also planted broad beans and garlic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I planted another kiwaï vine (&lt;em>Actinidia arguta&lt;/em>) because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the first one we planted 3 years ago has provided its first fruits this year and it tastes so good.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It’s auto-fertile which is easier than the regular kiwi vine (we have a male and female and for 8 years, we had flowers but no fruits).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Stay tuned!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Winter vegetables in January in years 1 and 10, by Charles Dowding</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/</guid><description>&lt;p>In January, Charles explains what he does and what grows in his garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Charles Dowding for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Charles Dowding&amp;rsquo;s channel.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nY32M39jQ1k">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-garden-area-how-is-it-going">New garden area: how is it going&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Charles created &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rA66WaH6Cu0&amp;amp;t=0s">a playlist&lt;/a> of how this area progressed through the month, starting a year ago (January 2021; the vlog was shot in January 2022.).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pigeon-deer-and-rabbit-damage">Pigeon, deer and rabbit damage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The wildlife will come to your garden, especially in the country side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pigeons &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/nY32M39jQ1k?t=96">peck the leaves&lt;/a>, leaving the veins of the plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/chard-eaten-by-deer.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/chard-eaten-by-deer_hu4ada7b9951357a8008835d30d17302d5_260386_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/chard-eaten-by-deer_hu4ada7b9951357a8008835d30d17302d5_260386_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/chard-eaten-by-deer_hu4ada7b9951357a8008835d30d17302d5_260386_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Swiss chard probably eaten by a deer"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can use some protection like a meshed tunnel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, with a simple wood structure and a net, you will keep the bird away from the crops you are still harvest from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/cabbages-undercover.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/cabbages-undercover_hu028b80ee9c29c17c1139d3242b9076c8_193002_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/cabbages-undercover_hu028b80ee9c29c17c1139d3242b9076c8_193002_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/cabbages-undercover_hu028b80ee9c29c17c1139d3242b9076c8_193002_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cabbage under a wood structure with a bird net"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cover-crop">Cover crop&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Charles uses broad beans quite a lot to cover the areas not used during the winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then he cuts them off in early may and put them on the compost heap.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="broccoli-and-birds">Broccoli and birds&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To protect the broccoli from the birds, you can build a simple structure the one below, made of some wood and a bird net.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The net doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to go all the way to the ground.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It depends on your birds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, it helps a bit with the wind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spinach">Spinach&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2023-01-10-spinach-under-a-tunnel.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bed of spinach"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="claytonia-_winter-purslane_-salad">Claytonia &lt;em>winter purslane&lt;/em> salad&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/claytonia-salad.jpg"
width="600"
height="312"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/claytonia-salad_hu407b067565a03cd31a151e3c1d162ed2_254127_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/claytonia-salad_hu407b067565a03cd31a151e3c1d162ed2_254127_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/claytonia-salad_hu407b067565a03cd31a151e3c1d162ed2_254127_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Claytonia winter purslane salad"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="461px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks very productive for January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m wondering where I could find some seeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The seedlings were planted in October.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="raspberries">Raspberries&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It will be time to cut off the stems as the new shoots will grow from the base in the spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="leaks">Leaks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/multi-sown-leaks.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/multi-sown-leaks_hubc777d374a0a2cc4a5724a955be333ee_235003_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/multi-sown-leaks_hubc777d374a0a2cc4a5724a955be333ee_235003_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/multi-sown-leaks_hubc777d374a0a2cc4a5724a955be333ee_235003_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Multi-sown leaks"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still in the ground in January, they’re going strong and will provide food up to April.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="no-dig-brussels-sprouts">No dig Brussels sprouts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-brussel-sprouts.jpg"
width="600"
height="311"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-brussel-sprouts_hu8923825510e877815db776e52291c9db_230124_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-brussel-sprouts_hu8923825510e877815db776e52291c9db_230124_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-brussel-sprouts_hu8923825510e877815db776e52291c9db_230124_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bed of second crop Brussels sprouts"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="192"
data-flex-basis="463px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d love to grow some!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles protects them with a bird net from being pecked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brussels sprouts are sown in March, planted in June.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pea-shoots">Pea shoots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-peas.jpg"
width="600"
height="309"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-peas_hufd0ae0b05099eef0bd577c1a8a903318_226158_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-peas_hufd0ae0b05099eef0bd577c1a8a903318_226158_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2023-01/winter-vegetables-in-january-charles-dowding/images/bed-of-peas_hufd0ae0b05099eef0bd577c1a8a903318_226158_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A bed of peas under a tunnel"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="194"
data-flex-basis="466px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles grows peas in January for the shoots, which you can eat in salads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He planted them in November.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To harvest the shoots, you pick the top and there will be more new shoots coming from the base.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It could produce shoot up until may. It depends on the winter harshness.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="making-your-own-potting-compost">Making your own potting compost&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You have dry compost? Sift it to 4 mm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting good potting compost from the gardening supermarket can yield surprising results, not always providing the same growth year over year.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dedicate-an-area-for-aromatic-herbs">Dedicate an area for aromatic herbs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Having thyme, rosemary, sage, fennel and mints add flavor to the garden and the meals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once planted, you will need to add some woodchip yearly as the old ones break down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those plants don&amp;rsquo;t need a highly nutritious soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See how it looked back in June 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qrwy4U7kjtI&amp;amp;t=0s">in this vlog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>