<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>In Spring on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-spring/</link><description>Recent content in In Spring on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/in-spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring: sowing and planting into surface compost outside, by Charles Dowding</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/spring-sowing-and-planting-charles-dowding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-11/spring-sowing-and-planting-charles-dowding/</guid><description>&lt;p>When spring comes, it’s time to sow and plant your new crops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to Charles Dowding for sharing his wisdom and knowledge! I wrote the following notes watching the video published on Charles Dowding’s channel. You can watch it using &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qZs17nwxgtg">this YouTube link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="before-you-sow">Before you sow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You have applied compost on your beds with compost in the beginning of the past winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, before you sow your seeds, use a rake to break up the remaining lumps of compost to create a nice smooth surface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use your feet to break any lumps. Walking on a compost bed is fine because it needs to be firm and you can’t compact compost by walking on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sowing-carrots-with-radish">Sowing carrots with radish&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Draw lines with a wood stick (if you don’t own &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=triangular&amp;#43;hoe">a triangular hoe&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make them not too deep (about 3-4 cm).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sowing in compost is absolutely fine, unlike some may say.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-tip" id="Radish tip" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title">Radish tip&lt;/p>&lt;p>If you sow your radishes with your carrots, you will know where the carrots are. The first sprout very quickly while the latter take more time to come up.&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Finish the sowing with covering the lines drawn with compost and walk on the lines to firm the compost once again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="planting-seedlings-grown-in-modules">Planting seedlings grown in modules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The tool to perform the task is a spade handle which has a slightly pointed and round extremity that is perfect to make holes in the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can create your own with a tree branch or an old space handle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The width of the handle or branch should be about the same as the modules you’re going to plant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To plant lettuce, use a spacing of 25 cm so that you can let them grow big.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charles picks up the outer leaves to eat for a long period of time. It provides a lot of food from the same plants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you plant the seedlings, set them deep so they’re sturdier.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="covering-a-bed-with-fleece">Covering a bed with fleece&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When it’s still early spring, you may need to install a fleece (a white cover to protect the plants from the cold).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>