<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Badgers on Jérémie Litzler</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/tags/badgers/</link><description>Recent content in Badgers on Jérémie Litzler</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamjeremie.me/tags/badgers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gardening in 2022: observations, harvest and next year's plans</title><link>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-10-24-inside-a-kiwai.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gardening in 2022: observations, harvest and next year's plans" />&lt;p>What happened in the garden in 2022? We had a lot of volunteer crops, more badgers and a very dry year overall&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time planting, there were tasks to do in the garden!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s review all of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h2 id="pumpkins">Pumpkins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/pumking-in-a-oak-tree.jpg"
width="600"
height="1067"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/pumking-in-a-oak-tree_huc374e456501d63c9c34894ebf66ca1ff_805742_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/pumking-in-a-oak-tree_huc374e456501d63c9c34894ebf66ca1ff_805742_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/pumking-in-a-oak-tree_huc374e456501d63c9c34894ebf66ca1ff_805742_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A pumpoak, a pumpkin variety of Ardèche 🤣"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="134px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only volunteer crops grew up this year, all from last year compost area, where we put lots of autumn leaves and kitchen waste.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The plants grew very well, spreading along the fence and even up the oak tree. We had a couple of &lt;em>lanterns&lt;/em> in the tree, as you see above ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The harvest was better than 2020 (when we had picked 12.274 kg). This year, we reached 17.686 kg without any planting work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the pumpkins were very tasty so far. You can guess we won&amp;rsquo;t have much left before the winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/last-kuri-squash-harvested-in-october.jpg"
width="600"
height="450"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/last-kuri-squash-harvested-in-october_hua79a8a4b15ddc8c42a9179d649d6f837_179155_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/last-kuri-squash-harvested-in-october_hua79a8a4b15ddc8c42a9179d649d6f837_179155_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/last-kuri-squash-harvested-in-october_hua79a8a4b15ddc8c42a9179d649d6f837_179155_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Six kuri squashes"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="potatoes">Potatoes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A lot of volunteer crops came up this year. We planted a few in the spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We harvested 1150 grams only.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lemon-wort-_lemon-verbena_">Lemon wort (&lt;em>Lemon verbena&lt;/em>)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We harvested 3 times the lemon wort and we washed and dried it immediately using the solar-powered dehydrator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think we could have had one more if I harvested the stems earlier in June.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The quantity harvested, however, is enough for a year’s worth of herbal infusions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kiwai-actinidia-arguta">Kiwai (Actinidia arguta)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This year, the spring was mild and no frost hit the flowers of our kiwai vine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vine produced 220 g of fruits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/kiwai-harvest-2022.jpg"
width="600"
height="450"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/kiwai-harvest-2022_hu73fe37def016893216461c73621d10bf_222957_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/kiwai-harvest-2022_hu73fe37def016893216461c73621d10bf_222957_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/kiwai-harvest-2022_hu73fe37def016893216461c73621d10bf_222957_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="The kiwai&amp;rsquo;s harvest in 2022"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope next year will bring more. The vine has grown a little more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re planning to buy another one to plant in the next available area for gardening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kiwai are high in Vitamin C, even more than the regular kiwi fruit. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find a technical source, though, only a few web pages stating that fact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/images/2022-10-24-inside-a-kiwai.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="A kiwai fruit cut in half"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="raspberries">Raspberries&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It was a surprise when I saw over a dozen raspberries stems shoot out from the ground in spring. The winter blanket of dead leaves has probably helped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stems grew tall, but we had few fruits, just enough to eat on the spot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dry summer burnt almost of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The autumn water and nice weather, however, brought them back to life!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="black-currants">Black currants&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We planted three plants this year and it produces a few fruits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But like the rest, the lack of water almost killed them. However, the rain of late August brought hope and new leaves bloomed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the plants to grow so we can have fruits and make tincture from the blossom.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comfrey">Comfrey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The comfrey was strong again this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-danger" id=" To do Add a picture" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title"> To do Add a picture&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Like all the rest, the very dry summer didn&amp;rsquo;t spare the plant, but the very mild autumn so far has helped new leaves to grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I transplanted four young comfrey plants near the current compost area. So nice to be able to start reproduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dandelions">Dandelions&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-danger" id=" To do Add a picture" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title"> To do Add a picture&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had very nice and big dandelions instead of the rocket salad (that has died, I think, after 2 years of crops from the same plants). The leaves were large and lasted a few meals in the spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The roots are still there, so they will be back next spring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nettles">Nettles&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="jli-notice jli-notice-danger" id=" To do Add a picture" >
&lt;p class="jli-notice-title"> To do Add a picture&lt;/p>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>They’re spreading well. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t excite everyone in the family, but the roots are superficial and the top soil rather soft. So it’s easy to move the roots around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will probably more of them to the next composting area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to nettles for all sorts of reason: as a natural fertilizer, as food in soup or herbal infusion or even tinctures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tomatoes">Tomatoes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I purchased four tomato plants. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the year for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I only picked a few black cherry tomatoes and a nice pineapple tomato.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they lacked water in the summer, near the end of July and the beginning of August, when we weren’t there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if I put in the place the irrigation, the plants had dried up when we came back. What didn&amp;rsquo;t get eaten by the sheep, who made their way in the garden due to my negligence, was pretty weak&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We didn&amp;rsquo;t miss the tomatoes. We didn&amp;rsquo;t eat that much, even from our purchases in the local grocery store.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cover-crops-with-flax-seed-and-green-lentils">Cover crops with flax-seed and green lentils&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On August 12, 2022, I sowed some in different places after preparing the places with bought compost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I threw the seeds by hand and recovered with soil from an old raised bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On August 17, 2022, I covered the sprouting seeds with hay to keep the moisture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lentils growed well. The goal was to enrich the soil with the green waste, but, more importantly, with the nitrogen stored by the lentils.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On August 28, 2022, this is how the lentils looked like:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/lentils-growing-a-garden-bed.jpg"
width="600"
height="338"
srcset="https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/lentils-growing-a-garden-bed_hu82ac2fa77433f11b89aed902a7d26feb_271626_360x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 360w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/lentils-growing-a-garden-bed_hu82ac2fa77433f11b89aed902a7d26feb_271626_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 600w, https://iamjeremie.me/post/2022-10/gardening-in-2022/images/lentils-growing-a-garden-bed_hu82ac2fa77433f11b89aed902a7d26feb_271626_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Lentils growing a garden bed"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="badgers">Badgers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OK, those beasts have been generating trouble for two years now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’re probably looking for food, and they come to the garden to plow the ground, not matter what we planted in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year, the peas had to be replanted three times!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve planted almost nothing because I didn&amp;rsquo;t take time to find a solution to repel them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only in September, I installed a rabbit fencing where I think the badgers are coming through. We have fenced all around the garden because of the sheep, but the badgers found a hole big enough to sneak in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains to be seen if I did patch all the holes in the fence&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="next-years-plan">Next year&amp;rsquo;s plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I would love to plant more, to start to grow more vegetables to reach some partial autonomy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I plan&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>to start planting:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>garlic (from heads purchased at our organic grocery shop),&lt;/li>
&lt;li>board bean (&lt;em>Vicia faba L.&lt;/em>) to eat but mainly to capture the nitrogen in the air&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>then to continue with all I can plant, from lettuce, to spinach, round carrots and beets.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, the main job is to bring better soil, maybe even purchase a large amount of compost. It’s supposed to cost 115.5 euros for about one ton of 20 mm organic-compatible compost. 75% of the cost goes into transport (renting a truck).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>